#### **Lauren Noeltner**

### laurennoeltner@gmail.com

(404) 376-7192

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/lauren-noeltner-102b731a0

GitHub: <a href="https://www.github.com/LNoeltner1/">https://www.github.com/LNoeltner1/</a>
<a href="Portfolio">Portfolio</a>: <a href="https://lauren-noeltner.herokuapp.com/">https://lauren-noeltner.herokuapp.com/</a>

### **Career Summary**

Began working at 16 in a veterinary clinic, absorbing medical knowledge and soft-skills like client interaction in difficult situations. Continued to work at the clinic into college and would spend off time dog-sitting for clients in freelance business. Accepted a sales associate position in Athens in 2015 and promoted to the assistant manager several months later. Began working at a theater as floor staff upon returning to Atlanta. Promoted to Team Lead in 2019 and, shortly before COVID, to Senior Team Lead. Planning to change career paths for several years, began saving for a web development course.

# **Objective**

I chose to spend my time during the lockdown redirecting my career from sales/customer service to technology by expanding my knowledge of application development. To gain the skills necessary to make a career out of my passion, I attended Georgia Tech's full-time, Full Stack Flex Web Development bootcamp in 2020 and graduated with an A. I have developed and deployed many full-stack applications both by myself and with a team and am excited to use my skills in a professional setting.

#### **Technical Skills**

- Page Design: HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap, Foundation
- Primary Language: JavaScript
- Libraries/frameworks: React, Node, Express, jQuery, Handlebars, Axios, and many other Node packages
- Databases: MongoDB, MySQL, Sequelize, NoSQL
- Development Tools: Version control/deployment with GitHub and Heroku, Git, Visual Studio Code, MongoDB Atlas, Robo3T, MySQL Workbench, Postman, Chrome DevTools

#### **Education**

- Certificate in Full Stack Web Development, Georgia Institute of Technology, November 2020
- Relevant courses, University of Georgia
  - Color and Composition, 3D Design, Research Statistics, Psychology courses, Physics

# **Notable Projects**

- Cryptic Encounters
  - o Responsibilities: Front and Back End, dialogue mapping/logic, Design, Concept
  - o **Tech used:** JavaScript, Handlebars, Nodejs, Express, MySQL, Foundation
  - Link to Github: <a href="https://github.com/LNoeltner1/cryptic-encounters">https://github.com/LNoeltner1/cryptic-encounters</a>
  - Link to Deployment: <a href="https://cryptic-encounter.herokuapp.com/">https://cryptic-encounter.herokuapp.com/</a>
- GiddyltUp
  - o Responsibilities: Front and Back End, REST/CRUD management, Design, Concept
  - o Tech used: JavaScript, MongoDB, Express, React, Nodejs, Bootstrap, Animate.css
  - Link to Github: <a href="https://github.com/LNoeltner1/GiddyltUp">https://github.com/LNoeltner1/GiddyltUp</a>
  - Link to Deployment: https://giddyitup-eg.herokuapp.com/

- Online/Offline Budget Tracker
  - Responsibilities: Front and Back End (solo project)
  - o **Tech Used:** JavaScript, MongoDB, Nodejs, Express, Morgan
  - Link to GitHub: https://github.com/LNoeltner1/budget-tracker
  - o Link to Deployment: https://budget-tracker-Inoeltner.herokuapp.com/

# Work Experience

Senior Team Lead Regal Entertainment Group (Alpharetta, Georgia)—August 2020-Present

• See description below.

Team Lead Regal Entertainment Group (Atlanta, Georgia)—April 2019-August 2020

- Organizing and delegating tasks to floor staff to effectively run the theater
- Resolving customer complaints or comments in a way that everybody walked away happy
- Communicated effectively with upper management to coordinate all theater operations

Cast Member Regal Entertainment Group (Atlanta, Georgia)—February 2017-April 2019

- Interacted with customers positively and became a customer favorite over time
- Spent extra time cleaning to ensure a safe and healthy workspace for all
- Quickly became senior cashier because of my accurate accounting

Assistant Manager Victorious Vapors (Athens, Georgia)—June 2016-August 2016

- Managed all sales associates, ensuring that the store was running properly
- Consistently maintained top sales numbers (>\$55,000 over 8 months)
- Authored the employee manual to simplify the on-boarding process and set policies

Sales Associate Victorious Vapors (Athens, Georgia)—August 2015-June 2016

Developed a strong rapport with clients, creating a wide base of recurring, loyal customers

Dog-Sitter/Walker My freelance pet-care business (Atlanta, Georgia)—May 2012-Present

• Started my own side business of pet-care with great success and many recurring clients

Kennel Technician Briarcliff Animal Clinic (College Park, Georgia)—June 2008-August 2013

- Interviewed new clients and assisted doctors with treatments, diagnoses, and surgeries
- Maintained medical records and other necessary paperwork accurately and diligently
- Nominated by coworkers several times for an "Above and Beyond" award